Mss.Rec.107 Mss.Rec.107
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Arapaho Starhawk Society Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance, 1974-08-04; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:22:13; Fan Man, David; Good Bear, Howard; Hunter, Harrison; Orange, Jannelle; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sankey, Scotty; Sleeper, Stanley; Sutton, Marcella; Wilson, Danny Lee; Young Bear, Sam
    Recorded at Barefoot Park, near Canton, Oklahoma, August 4, 1974. Hosts: Starhawk Society (Stanley Sleeper, Chairman). Head Staff: Harrison Hunter (Sac and Fox), Head Singer; Other singers are Cheyenne, Caddo, Kiowa; Danny Lee Wilson (Delaware/Arapaho), Head Man Dancer; Jannelle Orange (Arapaho), Head Lady Dancer; Scotty Sankey (Arapaho), Head Little Boy Dancer; Marcella Sutton (Arapaho), Head Little Girl Dancer; Howard Good Bear and Sam Young Bear (Cheyenne/Arapaho), MCs; David Fan Man (Arapaho), substitute MC.
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [Side A], 1974-08-09; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:15; Brumley, Renae; Good Eagle, Ronnie; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce; Webb, Gerry; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at Skiatook Community Center, Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 9, 1974. Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman) (Members predominantly Osage). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; Ronnie Good Eagle (Osage/Sac and Fox/Comanche), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; Renae Brumley (Osage), Princess; Ed Red Eagle and Gerry Webb (Cherokee/Creek), MCs.
    Dance--Competitions; Fox dance; Osage dance; Ponca Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma; Skiatook (Okla.)
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance [Side B], 1974-08-09; 26-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:47; Brumley, Renae; Good Eagle, Ronnie; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce; Webb, Gerry; Wilson, Carrie Vee
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side A], 1974-08-10; 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:47; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
    Recorded at Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Ground, near Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 10, 1974. Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman) (Members predominantly Osage). Singers: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer, other singers are Ponca. Invited Dancers: Kiowa Gourd Clan. M.C. unidentified.
    Dance--Competitions; Osage dance; Ponca Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma; Skiatook (Okla.)
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Afternoon Gourd Dance [Side B], 1974-08-10; 27-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:55; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd and War Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-08-10; 28-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:05; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
    Recorded at Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Ground, near Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 10, 1974. Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman) (Members predominantly Osage). Singers: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer, other singers are Ponca. Kiowa Gourd Clan, invited Gourd Dancers. M.C. unidentified.
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd and War Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-08-10; 28-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:22; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd and War Dance (tape 2) [Side A], 1974-08-10; 29-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:16; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
    Recorded at Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Ground, near Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 10-11, 1974). Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer, other singers are Ponca. Invited Dancers: Kiowa Gourd Clan. M.C. unidentified.
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening Gourd and War Dance (tape 2) [Side B], 1974-08-10; 29-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:15; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce
    Recorded at Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Ground, near Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 10-11, 1974. Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer, other singers are Ponca. Invited Dancers: Kiowa Gourd Clan. M.C. unidentified.
  - Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow: Evening War Dance, 1974-08-11; 30-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:21; Brumley, Renae; Good Eagle, Ronnie; Red Eagle, Ed; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Rush, Joe; St. John, Perce; Webb, Gerry; Wilson, Carrie Vee
    Recorded at Skiatook Community Center, Skiatook, Oklahoma, August 11, 1974. Hosts: Kihekah Steh Pow-Wow Club (Perce St. John, Chairman). Head Staff: Joe Rush (Ponca), Head Singer; Ronnie Good Eagle (Osage/Sac and Fox/Comanche), Head Man Dancer; Carrie Vee Wilson (Quapaw), Head Lady Dancer; Renae Brumley (Osage), Princess; Ed Red Eagle and Gerry Webb (Cherokee/Creek), MCs.
    Dance--Competitions; Osage dance; Osage Indians--Music; Ponca dance; Powwows--Oklahoma; Skiatook (Okla.)
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-08-12; 31-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:41; Diebold, Ruby; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
    Recorded at Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Ground, Cowskin River, Ottawa County, Oklahoma, August 12, 1974. Hosts: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Organization (Bob White, Chief and Speaker). Principal Singers: Bob White (Seneca-Cayuga); Dutch White (Seneca-Cayuga); Frank Thomas (Eastern Iriquois, tribe uncertain); Bill Shawnee (Shawnee/Delaware). Other Singers and Dancers: members of the host ground, other "Eight Tribes" of Ottawa County, Shawnees from White Oak Ground, visiting Eastern Seneca and Cayuga from Grand River and New York State Reservations. Instruments: water drum, claves, horn and gourd rattles, (ceremonial) snapping turtle rattle, (Lead Dance) can or turtle shell, leg shackles.
    Cayuga dance; Cayuga Indians--Music; Ottawa County (Okla.); Powwows--Oklahoma; Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-08-12; 31-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:08; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 2) [Side A], 1974-08-12; 32-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:44; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
    Recorded at: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Ground, Cowskin River, Ottawa County, Oklahoma, August 12, 1974. Hosts: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Organization (Bob White, Chief and Speaker). Principal Singers: Bob White (Seneca-Cayuga); Dutch White (Seneca-Cayuga); Frank Thomas (Eastern Iriquois, tribe uncertain); Bill Shawnee (Shawnee/Delaware). Other Singers and Dancers: members of the host ground, other "Eight Tribes" of Ottawa County, Shawnees from White Oak Ground, visiting Eastern Seneca and Cayuga from Grand River and New York State Reservations. Instruments: water drum, claves, horn and gourd rattles, (ceremonial) snapping turtle rattle, (Lead Dance) can or turtle shell, leg shackles.
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 2) [Side B], 1974-08-12; 32-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:42; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side A], 1974-08-13; 33-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:27; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
    Recorded at Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Ground, Cowskin River, Ottawa County, Oklahoma, August 13, 1974. Hosts: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Organization (Bob White, Chief and Speaker). Principal Singers: Bob White (Seneca-Cayuga); Dutch White (Seneca-Cayuga); Frank Thomas (Eastern Iriquois, tribe uncertain); Bill Shawnee (Shawnee/Delaware). Other Singers and Dancers: members of the host ground, other "Eight Tribes" of Ottawa County, Shawnees from White Oak Ground, visiting Eastern Seneca and Cayuga from Grand River and New York State Reservations. Instruments: water drum, claves, horn and gourd rattles, (ceremonial) snapping turtle rattle, (Lead Dance) can or turtle shell, leg shackles.
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 1) [Side B], 1974-08-13; 33-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:41; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 2) [Side A], 1974-08-13; 34-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:39; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
    Recorded at: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Ground, Cowskin River, Ottawa County, Oklahoma, August 13, 1974. Hosts: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Organization (Bob White, Chief and Speaker). Principal Singers: Bob White (Seneca-Cayuga); Dutch White (Seneca-Cayuga); Frank Thomas (Eastern Iriquois, tribe uncertain); Bill Shawnee (Shawnee/Delaware). Other Singers and Dancers: members of the host ground, other "Eight Tribes" of Ottawa County, Shawnees from White Oak Ground, visiting Eastern Seneca and Cayuga from Grand River and New York State Reservations. Instruments: water drum, claves, horn and gourd rattles, (ceremonial) snapping turtle rattle, (Lead Dance) can or turtle shell, leg shackles.
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: Ceremonial and Stomp Dance (tape 2) [Side B], 1974-08-13; 34-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:59; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Shawnee, Bill; Thomas, Frank; White, Bob; White, Dutch
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: "Visitor's Night" War Dance [side A], 1974-08-15; 35-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:52; Blalock, Jim; Dick, Bill; Dougherty, Steve; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Vailer, George; White, Bob; White, Chris
    Recorded at Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Ground, Cowskin River, Ottawa County, Oklahoma, August 15, 1974. Hosts: Seneca-Cayuga Ceremonial Organization (Bob White, Chief and Speaker). Singers: Chris White (Shawnee/Delaware), leader; Bill Dick (Shawnee), Steve Dougherty (Shawnee), George Valier (Shawnee), Jay Blalock (Shawnee). No head staff was appointed, as this dance is a mini sequel or adjunct to the Green Corn Ceremony.
    Ottawa County (Okla.); Ponca Indians--Music; Powwows--Oklahoma; Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: "Visitor's Night" War Dance [side B], 1974-08-15; 35-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:44; Blalock, Jim; Dick, Bill; Dougherty, Steve; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Vailer, George; White, Bob; White, Chris
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: "Visitor's Night" Stomp Dance [side A], 1974-08-15; 36-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:57; Blackbird, John; Blackbird, Thomas; Dunberg, Paul; Kinder, Steve; Rains, Monty; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Sumpka, Robert; Urguhart, Bun; White Eagle, Mose; White, Bob; White, Chris
    Cherokee dance; Creek dance; Ottawa County (Okla.); Powwows--Oklahoma; Shawnee dance
  - Seneca-Cayuga Green Corn: "Visitor's Night" Stomp Dance [side B], 1974-08-15; 36-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:07; Blalock, Jay; Dick, Bill; Dougherty, Steve; Roark-Calnek, Sue N., 1936-; Valier, George; White, Bob; White, Chris
    Ottawa County (Okla.); Powwows--Oklahoma; Stomp dance